A Movie Like No Other
Moonwalker is a fantasy, music film directed by Colin Chilvers.
This fantastical movie inspired by the music of Michael Jackson features
imaginative interpretations of hit tracks from the iconic 1987 album “Bad”.
Michael, played by Michael Jackson.
Mr. Big, played by Joe Pesci.
Sean, played by Sean Ono Lennon.
Katie, played by Kelley Parker.
Zeke, played by Brandon Quintin Adams.
Maestro (segment "Badder"), played by Ben Aaron.
Moonwalker is a 1988 American experimental anthology
musical film starring Michael Jackson.
Rather than featuring one continuous narrative, the film expresses the influence of fandom and innocence through a
collection of short films about Jackson, several of which are long-form music videos from Jackson's 1987 album Bad.
The film is named after the dance technique known as the
moonwalk, which Jackson was known for performing.
The film was released theatrically in Europe and South America, but Warner Bros.
canceled plans for a Christmas 1988 theatrical release in the United States.
Moonwalker was released on VHS, and remained #1 on
Billboard's Video Chart for 22 weeks.
Moonwalker also spent 14 weeks at #1 on Billboards Top Video- Cassette sales chart In 1989, Moonwalker was honoured
with a certification of 800,000 copies sold by the Recording Industry Association of America (RIAA).
Moonwalker has been certified 9 x Platinum in the United Kingdom.
The "Leave Me Alone" video aired as a separate entity and won a Grammy in 1990 for Best Music
Video, Short Form, which is the only Grammy Award Jackson received for the album Bad.
"Leave Me Alone" video also won the Cannes Gold
Lion Award for Best Special Effects.
The film explores themes of dancing, drug crime, gangster, entertainer, parody.